（井藤ノノハ）な…　何？
What?
Hey! Wait, Kaito!
（少女時代のノノハ）
もう！　待ってよ　カイト！
（少年時代のカイト）へへ～ん！
やなこった～い！　ハハハハ。
Catch me if you can!
Come on! Wait, Kaito!
（ノノハ）こら！　待ってってば　カイト！
（カイト）イェーイ　イェーイ！　アハハハハ…。
What's going on? What's this I'm seeing?
何これ…　私　何見てるの？
昔の…　俺たち!?
Our past?!
（フリーセル）もしかして　これは→
Could this be the same kind of illusion you said he showed you?
カイトが見せられたっていう
幻の世界？
Indeed it is.
（真方ジン）そのとおり。
ジン！
Jin!
Welcome to Amgine—I mean, to my world, children of the Phi Brain.
ようこそ　アムギーネ…
いや　私の世界へ。→
ファイ・ブレインの子供たち…。
So that's...
じゃあ　あれが!?
オルペウス！
Orpheus!
（フリーセル）
僕たちが　アムギーネに来る事なんて
お見通しだったみたいだね。
So you knew we were coming to Amgine?
What are you trying to pull, Orpheus?
何のまねだ　オルペウス！
What's the point in showing this to us?
俺たちに　こんなもん見せて
一体　何たくらんでやがる!?
そいつは…。
What?!
You rejected my Armlets. Let me show you the true power of Phi Brain.
オルペウスの腕輪を拒絶した
お前たちに→
ファイ・ブレインの力の何たるかを
見せてやろう。
（フリーセル）ここは　一体…。
Where are we?
あれって…　カイトの
お父さんと　お母さん!?
Are those your parents, Kaito?
てめえ！
You bastard...
Stop!
やめろ～！
Mom! Dad!
父さん！　母さ～ん！
待って！　父さん　母さん！
Wait! Mom! Dad!
Kaito?
（大門シズカ）カイト!?
（大門アキラ）
お前は　来ては駄目だ！
You can't come!
これは　パズル…　パズルなんだよ！
だから　僕も一緒に行く！
This is a puzzle! I know it is!
Let me go with you!
カイト　ありがとう。
Thanks, Kaito!
エヘヘヘ。　僕に解けないパズルは
ないもんね～！
There's no puzzle I can't solve!
カイト！
カイト。
Kaito!
I can't breathe, Mom, Dad!
（カイト）苦しいよ～　父さん　母さん！
フフフッ。
父さん…　母さん…。
Mom... Dad...
しっかりするんだ！　カイト！
Get a grip, Kaito!
Mom...
Wait for me, Freecell!
（ソリティア）こら！　待ちなさい　フリーセル。
そのペンダントは　私のよ！
That's my pendant!
ハハハハハ！
や～だよ。　僕　これ欲しい！
Come on! Let me have it!
もう…　しかたないわね。
Oh well...
あっ…　リングがない!?
She doesn't have her Ring?!
（ソリティア）これで　どう？
How about this?
うわ～　ママ　ありがとう！
Thanks, Mom!
お礼を言うのは
ママの方よ。
え？
I should be thanking you.
覚えてないかもしれないけど→
You probably don't remember.
ママが　オルペウス・リングを
つけられそうになった時→
You were still little. When I was about to put on the Orpheus Ring,
小さかった　あなたが
大泣きしてね。→
you started crying like never before.
その時に気付いたの。→
That helped me realize what a dangerous thing it was
「これは危険なものだ。
つけちゃいけない」って…。
and that I mustn't put it on.
ふ～ん。
It's thanks to you protecting me back then that I can be happy with you now.
あなたが守ってくれたおかげで
ママは今　幸せよ。
ありがとう　フリーセル。
あ…。
Thanks, Freecell.
Mom...
Interfere with the past and change the future.
（ジン）
過去に干渉し　未来を変える。
That's the true power of the Phi Brain.
これが　ファイ・ブレインの持つ
本当の力だ。
I'd rather die than let you touch my past!
過去に干渉するなんて
俺は認めねえ！
It's all fake,
全部　いかさまだ！　どんなトリックを
使ったか知らねえけどな！
whatever tricks you used!
Oh?
I've had enough of puzzles!
（ノノハ）もぉ～　パズルなんて無理！
How can I solve them like you do?
どうやったら
カイトみたいにできるの～？
エヘヘッ　さあな～。
Who knows?
ねえ　ここ　どうすればいい？
しょうがないな～。
What do I do with this one?
You're hopeless.
できた！
I solved it!
やったね。
私も　パズルができた！→
Good job.
I can puzzle too!
パズルができるのって
こんなに気持ちいいんだ。→
I had no idea it feels this good to complete a puzzle!
知らなかった～。
うん　うん。
パズルって楽しい。
Puzzles are fun!
もっともっと教えて　カイト！
Teach me more, Kaito!
だ～め。　これからは
自分の力でやらなきゃ。
え？
Nope.
You must do the rest by yourself.
もっともっと難しいパズルに挑戦して
１人で解く。→
Challenge more and more difficult puzzles,
and solve them by yourself.
It's even more fun that way.
その方が　もっともっと
楽しいよ。
そう…。
Oh...
ノノハが　パズルを…？
Nonoha's puzzling?
いつまで　くだらねえもんを
見せてやがんだ！
When will you get bored of this folly?
No... I...
違う。　これって…。
Itou
（シズカ）はい　大門です。→
Hello? Daimon residence.
ええ…　はい…　えっ!?
I see. Yes.
What?
（ドアの開く音）
（シズカ）カイト！　ノノハちゃんが…。
Kaito! Nonoha's in the hospital!
（カイト）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。→
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
カイト。
大丈夫？　ノノハ　どうしたの？
Kaito?
Are you okay?
What happened?
うん…　ちょっと食べ過ぎて
おなか　こわしちゃって。
I just ate too much so I got sick.
よいしょ。　もう平気なの？
Are you fine now?
えっと…　ううん。
え？
Uh... no.
（ノノハ）また　パズル
できなくなっちゃったの。
I can't puzzle anymore.
えっ？
せっかく　カイトが
教えてくれたのに…。
Even though you taught me...
そ…　そんなの大丈夫だよ。
No worries! I'll solve all the puzzles in your stead!
僕が　ノノハの代わりに
パズル　ぜ～んぶ解くから！
あ…　ほんとに？
うん！　約束。
Really?
Yeah! Promise!
だから
早く元気になって　ノノハ。
So get well soon!
Okay!
Pinky promise, if I lie I will drink 1000 needles and cut my pinky.
私…　カイトが　パズル解くところを
見るのが大好きだった。
I really liked seeing you solve puzzles.
ずっと…　ずっとずっと
見ていたかったのに→
I just wanted to keep watching you,
カイトが　もう見せてくれないって
言うから　悲しくて　さみしくて→
but you said you wouldn't let me anymore.
I felt so sad and abandoned...
So I went and binged ate.
私　やけ食いしたんだった。
あれから　ほんとに　パズル
解けなくなっちゃったんだっけ。
I haven't been able to solve puzzles since then, huh?
I totally forgot about this.
ずっと忘れてた　こんな思い出。
ううん…　忘れた事にしてたんだ。
More like I tried to forget.
You tried to forget?
忘れた事にしていた　思い出？
じゃあ　これは…。
Then this is real?
（ジン）お前たちが見ていたものは
紛れもなく　お前たちの過去。→
What you've all seen is your real pasts
and the world as it would be if I interfered with your past.
そして　その過去に干渉し
私が変化させた世界だ。→
But I'm not perfect yet.
しかし　私は　まだ完全ではない。→
I can only show you the past or the changed world.
本物の過去も　作り替えた現実も
見せる事しかできない。
だが　完全なファイ・ブレインとなれば
私は時間を越え→
However, if I become a perfect Phi Brain, I'll surpass time,
神を超えた力を手にする。
and gain a power that exceeds the gods themselves.
過去に干渉し
現実を変える力をな。→
The power to alter the past and thus change reality.
If you knew this, I bet you wouldn't have rejected my Armlets.
それを分かっていれば
お前たちも→
この腕輪を捨てる事は
なかったのではないか？→
The Armlets choose those that are suited to become my vessels,
この腕輪は　私の器となりうる者を
選び　契約を結ぶ。
and bind them with a contract.
そのために作ったもの。
何!?
That's what I made them for.
What?
By putting on the armlet, you can rid yourself of emotions,
腕輪をつける事で
感情をそぎ落とし→
forcibly release the idle areas of your brain, and grow into a Phi Brain.
脳の領域が強制解放され
ファイ・ブレインへの成長を促すのだ。→
Take it.
さあ　受け取れ。　今のお前たちなら
腕輪をつければ→
As you are now, you could become the Phi Brain instantly by putting the Armlet on.
すぐにでも　ファイ・ブレインとなる事が
できるだろう。→
You are capable of that.
お前たちには資格がある。→
Capable of what countless geniuses could only dream of: surpassing the gods.
あまたの天才たちが望んでも
手に入れられなかった→
神々を超える資格がな。
カイトたちを　ファイ・ブレインにして
体を乗っ取るつもりなんでしょ!?
You just want to make them Phi Brain and take their bodies, right?
I'm not gonna let you do that!
そんな事は　絶対にさせない！
私は　肉体を必要としてはいるが
人生まで奪うつもりはない。
I do need a body, but I have no interest in taking your lives.
え？
どういう事だ？
What do you mean?
お前たちも知ってのとおり
真方ジンの精神は消えていない。
As you know, Makata Jin's mind is still intact.
ここにある。→
He's in here.
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちよ
私の精神を　受け入れ→
You would only need to become the vessel of my mind for five—no, just one year.
５年…　いや　１年
私に貸してくれれば　それでいい。
One year? What can you achieve in just a year?
１年？　たった１年で
何をする気なんだ？
（ジン）この世に生まれたからには
神々に挑み　神々を超える。→
Those born in this world should challenge and surpass the gods.
それが　人の進むべき道。
That's the path men should take.
決断しろ　ファイ・ブレインの子供たち。
Decide, children of the Phi Brain.
私に　無為な時間を使わせるな。→
Don't make me waste my time.
I can erase Makata Jin's mind at any time if I want to.
その気になれば　真方ジンの精神を
消す事など　たやすいのだぞ。
心の声
俺が　ファイ・ブレインになれば
ジンを救える。→
If I became the Phi Brain, I can save Jin.
Not only that. I could change the past and save Mom and Dad too.
いや…　それだけじゃない。→
過去を変えて
父さんと母さんを…。→
Then...
そうすれば…。
カイト！　カイトったら！
あ？
Kaito!
Hey, Kaito!
おう！　おはよう　ノノハ。
おはようじゃないわよ～　もう。
Hey! Morning, Nonoha!
Don't give me that!
はい　これ！　お弁当！
また忘れたでしょ。
いっけね。
Here, your lunch. You forgot it again.
Whoopsie.
おばさんのお弁当が泣くよ。
分かってるって。
You shouldn't treat the lunch your mom made you like that.
Yeah, I know...
今　ちょっと
追い込みの時期なんだよ。
There's just so much on my mind.
パズルの大会　近いんだっけ？
ああ。
That puzzle tournament's getting close?
Yeah! This year I'm gonna win for sure!
今年こそ　必ず優勝してみせるぜ！
全日本パズル選手権！
I'll get on the Japanese national puzzler team!
アハハハハ　無理無理。
今年は僕が優勝するんだから。
Dream on!
This year I'm gonna win.
フリーセル。
君は今年も定位置でいいよ。
Freecell?
You should just accept your destiny,
Kaito The Forever-Third.
万年３位の　カイト君。
う～。
Shut it! This year I'm gonna beat you all!
うっせえ！　今年こそ　お前ら
みんなまとめて倒してやるぜ！
Oh? I'm looking forward to that.
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
ほぅ　それは楽しみだ。
It doesn't matter how much you struggle,
君たち２人が　どうあがこうと
今年の優勝も　僕が頂く。
I'll emerge victorious again this year.
ルーク。
ヘッ！
Rook...
いつまでも　でかい口
たたかせねえぜ　会長さんよ！
You'll pay for that attitude eventually, prez!
もうすぐ授業始まるぞ～。
走れ～！
Classes are starting soon! Hurry up!
（フリーセル）学園長に真方先生。
It's the principal and Mr. Makata.
ヘヘヘッ　ジン！
Jin!
今日の放課後も
パズル部で特訓　よろしくな！
I'm looking forward to training at the puzzle club today after class!
こら　カイト。　学校では
「真方先生」と呼べと言っただろ。
Come on, Kaito. I told you to call me Mr. Makata at school.
By becoming the Phi Brain, you could even make this the reality.
（ジン）ファイ・ブレインになれば
こんな現実を作る事も可能だ。
You would be able to erase your tough past.
（ジン）つらい過去も
消し去る事ができる。
If you become the Phi Brain...
（ジン）ファイ・ブレインになれば…。
ファイ・ブレインに…　なれば…。
If I become the Phi Brain...
ん？　解いてみるか？
Wanna give it a try?
えっ　いいの？
私に　できるかなあ。
May I?
But can I really do it?
No.
違う…。
（２人）え？
ちっが～う！
No!
わっ!?　ぐっ…。
目を覚ませ～！
Wake up already!
You too!
もう一丁！
あががががが…。
てい！
うぐっ。
痛たたた…。
何しやがんだ　ノノハ！
What are you doing, Nonoha?
だって　あんなの
本当の私たちじゃないもん！
That's not us!
Huh?
えっ？
やっぱり
過去は変えちゃ駄目だよ。
You're not supposed to change the past!
いろんな事があったけど
過去があるから今があるんだもん。
Sure we've experienced some good times and bad times,
but it's because of that past that we have a present!
いろんな事があったから　カイトとも
フリーセル君とも会えたんだもん！
It's thanks to all everything, the good and bad, that I could meet you two!
ノノハ…。
Nonoha...
私　パズルが解けなくてもいい。
I'm fine with not being able to solve puzzles.
だって　つらくないもん。
It's not tough at all.
パズルを解くカイトと　パズルを解いている
みんなを見ていられたら→
I can still watch Kaito and everyone else solve puzzles.
That's enough to make me happy.
それで幸せ。
ありがとう　あの時の私。
I should thank my old self.
おかげで　今でも
カイトは　パズルバカだよ。
It's thanks to her that you're still a puzzle freak.
うるせえよ…。
Oh, shut up.
Mom...
ノノハ　君の言うとおりだ。→
Nonoha, you're right.
あの過去があるから…。
Who I am today is because of my past.
Yeah. Those memories make us who we are now, Orpheus!
ああ！
みんなの思い出があるから…→
今の俺たちがあるんだよ　オルペウス！
I've made up my mind! I'm not gonna become the Phi Brain!
決めたぜ
俺は　ファイ・ブレインには　ならねえ！
何？
What?
I don't want the power to change the past!
過去を変える…
そんな力　必要ねえ！
Surpassing the gods is man's destined path?
神を超えるのが　人の進む道？
Who cares about that crap?!
そんなもん　くそくらえだ！
オルペウス　てめえの思いどおりには
させねえ。
Orpheus, I'm not gonna let you have your way!
I'm gonna beat you and save Jin!
俺は　お前を倒し　ジンを助ける！
そんな事ができるとでも？
できるさ。
You honestly think that's possible?
Of course it is! There's no puzzle I can't solve!
俺に解けないパズルは　ねえ～！
We're... back?
戻って…　きたのか…。
Daimon Kaito...
（ジン）大門カイト…。→
私の見た未来と異なる
行動と結論を導き出すとは→
He came up with a course of action and a conclusion different from the future I envisioned.
Fascinating.
面白い。→
So the future is full of uncertainty, huh?
未来は不確定要素で満ちている
という事か…。
Very well.
それもよかろう。
エニグマ　進捗状況は？
Enigma, progress report.
The Puzzle of God?
（エニグマ）神のパズルですね。
作業は順調です。
The works are going according to schedule.
それでいい。
Good.
（せき）
（レイツェル）ジン！
Jin!
負担が大きすぎたか…。
Was the strain too much?
ジン！
Jin!
Jin, wake up!
ジン　しっかりして。
あ～　驚いた。
Phew, that caught me off guard.
I didn't expect to be shown memories I'd forgotten.
まさか　忘れていた思い出を
見せられるなんて思わなかった。
Yeah, it was surprising.
ああ　びっくりしたよ。→
「ファイ・ブレインは時間を超越する」か。→
The Phi Brain can conquer time...
But I don't get it.
でも　分からないな。
え？
What?
オルペウスが言った言葉。
What Orpheus said before.
１年だけ　体を貸してくれればいい
っていうのは→
Why did he say it'd be enough if we let him borrow our bodies for just a year?
どういう意味なんだろう？
う～ん…。
（フリーセル）何を焦っているんだ？
オルペウスは。
What is he scared of?
ヘッ！
焦ってもらおうじゃねえか。
Heh, he's right to be scared!
ハァ。
行こうぜ
やつが用意した　パズルによ！
Let's go and see this puzzle he made!
I'll solve whatever he came up with in a flash
どんなパズルも　片っ端から解いて→
and screw up all his precious schemes!
やつの　たくらみ
全部　ぶっ潰してやる！
カイト。
うん　行こう。
Kaito...
Yeah, let's go!
（逆之上ギャモン）
ヘッ！　カイトたちが　いねえと→
It's nice how quiet the academy is without those two here.
学園が静かで　いいやな。
But this isn't right, is it?
けどよ…
これでいいわけねえよな。→
I got called out by Orpheus too.
俺も　オルペウスさんのご指名を
受けた以上は…。
（姫川エレナ）ガリレオ。
あ？
Galileo!
Hmm?
Antoinette?
（ギャモン）アントワネット！
はい　アムギーネ行きの航空券。
Your flight ticket to Amgine.
What—
お前…。
行かないの？
そんなわけないわよね。
You're not going?
I can't really see that happening.
Oh geez, Mistress Elena.
…ったく　エレナ様はよぉ。
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
ああ…　大丈夫だ。
ジン…　ジンなのね！
Jin! You're Jin, right?
心配してたんだから。
もう戻ってこないと思って。
I was so worried you'd never return!
すまないな。
Sorry.
（レイツェル）よかった　本当に…。
I'm glad... I'm so glad!
（ジン）でも　時間は限られている。
I don't have much time though. I can only stay myself for a little while.
俺が俺でいられるのは
ほんの僅かだ。
レイツェル　俺から離れろ。
Raetsel, get away from me.
カイトたちも　決して
近づけてはならない。
えっ？
Kaito and his friends mustn't come either.
What?
オルペウスに新たな体を
与えては駄目だ。
You mustn't hand your body over to Orpheus.
だが　この体に居続ければ
やつは　いずれ滅びる。
If he stays in this body, he's bound to fall eventually.
な…　何を言ってるの!?　ジン。
What are you saying, Jin?
限界なんだ。　この体は　もう…。
My body's at its limits.
そんな…
うそでしょ!?　ジン！
No way! That can't be, Jin!
（ジン）逝く時は
オルペウスも道連れだ…。→
When I die, I'll take him with me.
だから　レイツェル…。
Please, Raetsel.
（レイツェル）駄目よ　ジン
そんな事　言わないで！→
That won't do, Jin!
Don't say stuff like that!
私が何とかするから。
I'll do something about it!
Oh? Then will you become the Phi Brain?
では　お前が　ファイ・ブレインとなるか？
（ジン）私は　誰でもよいのだ。→
I don't care who it is.
完全な　ファイ・ブレインに
なるためならば→
As long as I can become the perfect Phi Brain, I don't mind sacrificing all of mankind.
全ての人類を犠牲にしても
私は一向に構わん。
全ては　神を超えるためのパズルだ。
It is all but a puzzle to surpass the gods.
これが…。
Is this it?
（フリーセル）
オルペウスが用意した　試練のパズル。
It's the puzzle trial Orpheus prepared.
If you solve this, you'll become able to beat Orpheus?
これを解いていけば
オルペウスを倒せるようになるの？
Who knows?
さあな。　だが　やるしかねえ！
But what choice do we have?
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
It's puzzle time!
Preview
Welcome to this POG Airlines flight.
This is the pilot, Bishop.
We're almost at Amgine. Wait for me, Freecell!